DENIS KIPKEMBOI

Personal Details

Date of birth: 9th May 1996, Email:deniskem.dev@gmail.com

Phone: +254724974848

Country: Kenya

github: https://github.com/denisdevke

Profile

Accomplished Senior Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience leading projects by acting as architect, developer and programmer analyst. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. Strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

Work Experience

Remote developer at Futurenow LLC, Dubai, UAE

Jan 2021 – Aug 2022

Futurenow is a software development company. I worked as a Node js api developer and Flutter mobile app developer. We worked as a team and developed a number of applications including mobile apps and web apps.

Software developer and designer at Techlup, Eldoret, Kenya

May 2019 – present

Started a data management and software development incubation that includes a group of three individuals whose primary role is to develop software and manage data. We develop native android apps using Java and web apps using Laravel for backend and React js for UI.

Freelance expert at Chegg, Mumbai, India

Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

Chegg is an online platform to help students solve their homework. I work as an expert to solve programming-related questions in python, PHP, c++, and java.

Education

1. Diploma in ICT, RVTTI, Eldoret.

```
September 2017 – Feb 2021
```

2. Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, Tembelio Secondary School.

```
February 2012 – November 2016
```

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education, Tendwo Primary School. January 2002–
2011

Technical skills

- problem-solving and testing and debugging.
- Maintenance of workspaces.
- Computer programming C++, Python, Java, PHP, JavaScript, node.js.
- Strong communication skills
- Team work.

Tech Stack

- Web developer (Laravel + React js or Node js + React).
- Mobile developer (Flutter).
- Native android developer(Java + XML).
- Windows app developer(C# or VB).
- Rest API(Node js or Laravel).
- Database(MYSQL, Firebase and Mongo db).

Hobbies

- Computer programming
- Listening to music
- Meeting and interacting with people of different diversity
- Do It Your (DIY) self-projects and challenges.

Referee

Mr Lagat-Lecturer, RVTTI Eldoret.

+254713943500

Dennis - Team leader, Futurenow LLC Dubai.

+971564123203.